<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<checkstyle-metadata>
  <module>
    <check name="CommentsIndentationCheck" fully-qualified-name="com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.checks.indentation.CommentsIndentationCheck" parent="com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.TreeWalker">
      <description><![CDATA[<p>
 Controls the indentation between comments and surrounding code.
 Comments are indented at the same level as the surrounding code.
 Detailed info about such convention can be found
 <a href="https://checkstyle.org/styleguides/google-java-style-20180523/javaguide.html#s4.8.6.1-block-comment-style">
 here</a>
 </p><p>
 Please take a look at the following examples to understand how the check works:
 </p><p>
 Example #1: Block comments.
 </p><p>
 Example #2: Comment is placed at the end of the block and has previous statement.
 </p><p>
 Example #3: Comment is used as a single line border to separate groups of methods.
 </p><p>
 Example #4: Comment has distributed previous statement.
 </p><p>
 Example #5: Single line block comment is placed within an empty code block.
 Note, if comment is placed at the end of the empty code block, we have
 Checkstyle's limitations to clearly detect user intention of explanation
 target - above or below. The only case we can assume as a violation is when
 a single line comment within the empty code block has indentation level that
 is lower than the indentation level of the closing right curly brace.
 </p><p>
 Example #6: 'fallthrough' comments and similar.
 </p><p>
 Example #7: Comment is placed within a distributed statement.
 </p><p>
 Example #8: Comment is placed within an empty case block.
 Note, if comment is placed at the end of the empty case block, we have
 Checkstyle's limitations to clearly detect user intention of explanation
 target - above or below. The only case we can assume as a violation is when
 a single line comment within the empty case block has indentation level that
 is lower than the indentation level of the next case token.
 </p><p>
 Example #9: Single line block comment has previous and next statement.
 </p><p>
 Example #10: Comment within the block tries to describe the next code block.
 </p>]]></description>
      <properties>
        <property name="tokens" type="int[]" default-value="SINGLE_LINE_COMMENT,BLOCK_COMMENT_BEGIN">
          <description><![CDATA[tokens to check]]></description>
        </property>
      </properties>
      <message-keys>
        <message-key key="comments.indentation.block"/>
        <message-key key="comments.indentation.single"/>
      </message-keys>
    </check>
  </module>
</checkstyle-metadata>
